<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Run Nym Nodes on Nym Docs</title><link>https://nymtech.net/docs/run-nym-nodes/</link><description>Recent content in Run Nym Nodes on Nym Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://nymtech.net/docs/run-nym-nodes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Incentives</title><link>https://nymtech.net/docs/run-nym-nodes/incentives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nymtech.net/docs/run-nym-nodes/incentives/</guid><description>We will get into building the Nym codebase and running nodes in the next section. Before we do so, a note on token incentives.
The Nym network has some of the same overall goals as Tor. But we want to enable Nym to scale in response to increased demand (and shrink when demand drops, so as not to waste resources). To do this in a decentralized way, nodes are included in the network based on cryptocurrency bonding, and a system of delegated staking.</description></item><item><title>Building Nym</title><link>https://nymtech.net/docs/run-nym-nodes/build-nym/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nymtech.net/docs/run-nym-nodes/build-nym/</guid><description>This page details how to build the main Nym platform code, in Rust. If you want to build and run a validator, go here instead.
Nym runs on Mac OS X, Linux, and Windows. Windows should be considered experimental - it works fine if you&amp;rsquo;re an app developer but isn&amp;rsquo;t recommended for running nodes.
Prerequisites:
on Debian/Ubuntu: sudo apt install pkg-config build-essential libssl-dev curl jq. Rust 1.47 or later, with cargo.</description></item><item><title>Mixnodes</title><link>https://nymtech.net/docs/run-nym-nodes/mixnodes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nymtech.net/docs/run-nym-nodes/mixnodes/</guid><description>The Nym mixnode was built in the building nym section. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet built Nym and want to run the code, go there first.
To join the Nym testnet as a mixnode, copy the nym-mixnode binary from the target/release directory up to your server (or compile it on the server).
Upgrading from an earlier version If you have already been running a node on the Nym network v0.</description></item><item><title>Validators</title><link>https://nymtech.net/docs/run-nym-nodes/validators/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nymtech.net/docs/run-nym-nodes/validators/</guid><description>Nym validators secure the network with a staking token, defending the network from Sybil attacks.
Validators also provide privacy-enhanced credentials based on the testimony of a set of decentralized, blockchain-based issuing authorities. Nym validators use a signature scheme called Coconut to issue credentials. This allows privacy apps to generate anonymous resource claims through decentralised authorities, then use them with Service Providers.
The validator is built using Cosmos SDK and Tendermint, with a CosmWasm smart contract controlling the directory service, node bonding, and delegated mixnet staking.</description></item><item><title>Requesters</title><link>https://nymtech.net/docs/run-nym-nodes/requester/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nymtech.net/docs/run-nym-nodes/requester/</guid><description>The nym-network-requester was built in the building nym section. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet built Nym and want to run the code on this page, go there first.
If you have access to a server, you can run the nym-network-requester, which allows Nym users to make outbound network requests from your server.
The nym-network-requester is NOT an open proxy. It ships with a file called allowed.list.sample, which contains URLs used by the Blockstream Green and Electrum cryptographic wallets.</description></item><item><title>Gateways</title><link>https://nymtech.net/docs/run-nym-nodes/gateways/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nymtech.net/docs/run-nym-nodes/gateways/</guid><description>Gateways The Nym gateway was built in the building nym section. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet built Nym and want to run the code, go there first.
Gateways provide a destination for mixnet packets. Most of the internet doesn&amp;rsquo;t use encrypted Sphinx packets, so the gateway acts as a destination, sort of like a mailbox, for messages.
If you would like to run a gateway for the network, please contact us.</description></item><item><title>Mixnode Troubleshooting FAQ</title><link>https://nymtech.net/docs/run-nym-nodes/troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nymtech.net/docs/run-nym-nodes/troubleshooting/</guid><description>How can I tell my node is up and running and mixing traffic? To check from the machine your node is running on: To double check from your local machine Why is my node not mixing any packets &amp;amp; Setting up the firewall How can I make sure my node works from my local machine if I&amp;rsquo;m behind NAT and have no fixed IP address ? Can I use a different port other than 1789 ?</description></item></channel></rss>