<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Overview on Nym Docs</title><link>https://nymtech.net/docs/overview/</link><description>Recent content in Overview on Nym Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://nymtech.net/docs/overview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Nym Platform</title><link>https://nymtech.net/docs/overview/nym-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nymtech.net/docs/overview/nym-platform/</guid><description>We are currently running a testnet with Nym validators and mixnodes. Together, the validators and mixnodes provide integrated access control and network privacy to users of the Nym platform. They are assisted by several other platform components: multiple types of clients, and gateway nodes.
Here&amp;rsquo;s an overview of the entire network.
The Nym platform includes mixnodes, validators, gateways, and client code used for talking to the network. All of this is run in a decentralized, trustless fashion.</description></item><item><title>Network Privacy</title><link>https://nymtech.net/docs/overview/network-privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nymtech.net/docs/overview/network-privacy/</guid><description>When you send data across the internet, it can be recorded by a wide range of observers: your ISP, internet infrastructure providers, large tech companies, and governments.
Even if the content of a network request is encrypted, observers can still see that data was transmitted, its size, frequency of transmission, and gather metadata from unencrypted parts of the data (such as IP routing information). Adversaries may then combine all the leaked information to probabilistically de-anonymize users.</description></item><item><title>Coconut</title><link>https://nymtech.net/docs/overview/private-access-control/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nymtech.net/docs/overview/private-access-control/</guid><description>Introducing Coconut Coconut is a cryptographic signature scheme that produces privacy-enhanced credentials. It lets application programmers who are concerned with resource access control to think and code in a new way.
Most of the time, when we build system security, we think of who questions:
Has Alice identified herself (authentication)? Is Alice allowed to take a specific action (authorisation)? Coconut fundamentally changes these questions. Rather than asking who a user is, it allows application designers to ask different questions, mostly centred around questions of rights:</description></item><item><title>Links</title><link>https://nymtech.net/docs/overview/links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nymtech.net/docs/overview/links/</guid><description>Here are some links that may prove handy as you start exploring.
The Nym Project You can chat to us in Keybase. Download the app, then click Teams -&amp;gt; Join a team. Type nymtech.friends into the team name and hit continue. For general chat, hang out in the #general channel. Our development takes places in the #dev channel. Node operators should be in the #node-operators channel to receive notice of system updates or node downtime.</description></item></channel></rss>